Welcome to the Sensor Fusion module.
センサーフュージョンモジュールへようこそ
Sensor Fusion has a car or any sensing robot for
センサーフュージョンでは 車両または車両関連の感知ロボットを使って
that matter, understand and track its environment.
環境を認識し 追跡します
&gt;&gt; The environment could consist of other cars, or barriers on the shoulder
&gt;&gt; 環境は 他の車両、道路の路肩のガードレール
of the road, or motorcycles, or pedestrians walking across the road.
オートバイ道路を横断する歩行者などで 構成されます
&gt;&gt; Don't hit the pedestrians.
&gt;&gt; 歩行者をひかないで
&gt;&gt; That's right, don't hit the pedestrians.
&gt;&gt; そう 歩行者をひかないで
&gt;&gt; We'll get to that.
&gt;&gt; 絶対にね
First, I want you all to meet a few people.
まずは メンバーを紹介します
This is Michael Maile, the Director of the Sensor Fusion Team at Mercedes-Benz.
こちらはメルセデスベンツのセンサーフュージョンチームの ディレクター マイケル・メイルです
&gt;&gt; Hello.
&gt;&gt; こんにちは
&gt;&gt; And also from Mercedes-Benz,
&gt;&gt; 同じくメルセデスベンツのエンジニアで
we're joined by two engineers on Michael's team, Andrei Vatavu.
マイケルのチームに所属する アンドレイ・ヴァタヴ
&gt;&gt; Hi.
&gt;&gt; こんにちは
&gt;&gt; And Dominik Nuss.
&gt;&gt; そしてドミニク・ナス
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
&gt;&gt; ようこそ
&gt;&gt; By the end of this module, you'll implement your own
&gt;&gt; このモジュールでは 車両に対して相対的に歩行者を追跡する
sensor fusion algorithm to track a pedestrian relative to a car.
独自のセンサー フュージョンアルゴリズムを 実装します
To do this you'll need to fuse lidar and radar data.
これには ライダーとレーダーのデータを 融合する必要があります
You'll be working with a technique called a Kalman filter.
カルマンフィルターと呼ばれる手法を 使用します
You'll start with a basic Kalman filter and then Andre and
最初は基本的なカルマンフィルターを 使いますが
Dominic will help you extend it to more complex data.
アンドレイとドミニクが より複雑なデータに拡張するお手伝いをします
&gt;&gt; We're in the first lesson right now, in a moment,
&gt;&gt; これは 最初のレッスンです
Micheal will walk you through the basics of lidar and radar sensors.
この後マイケルが ライダーセンサーと レーダーセンサーの基本を説明します
&gt;&gt; In the second lesson, you'll be with Sebastian.
&gt;&gt; 2番目のレッスンでは セバスチャンが登場します
When it comes to the concept of Kalman filters, he's the best.
カルマンフィルターの概念といえば セバスチャンです
You'll work through part of Sebastian's AI for robotics course,
セバスチャンの ロボット工学AIを使って
in which you'll build a simplified Kalman filter in Python.
Pythonで簡易なカルマンフィルターを 作成します
If you've already taken Sebastian's course, feel free to skip ahead.
すでにセバスチャンのコースを受講している場合は スキップして構いません
&gt;&gt; Then we'll come to a big change.
&gt;&gt; その後大きな変化があります
&gt;&gt; You mean C++?
&gt;&gt; C++のこと?
&gt;&gt; Indeed.
&gt;&gt; そうです
&gt;&gt; Sensor fusion needs to happen quickly,
&gt;&gt; センサーフュージョンは 迅速に行う必要があります
which means we need to use a high performance language.
つまり 高性能言語を 使わなければなりません
C++ is a critical language for performing real-time operations.
C++はリアルタイム操作を実行する上で 重要な言語です
We use it as Mercedes and you use it to build your project in this module.
メルセデスではC++を採用しており このモジュールではプロジェクトの構築にC++を使います
&gt;&gt; So the third lesson is what are calling a C++ checkpoint.
&gt;&gt; 3番目のレッスンでは C++チェックポイントを呼び出します
You'll face some challenges that test your ability to apply C++ techniques.
C++の手法の適用能力をテストする 課題も出されます
Once you complete them, you're ready to build basic Kalman filters with C++.
課題を終えたら いよいよC++で基本的なカルマンフィルターを作成します
&gt;&gt; So, what if you don't already know C++?
&gt;&gt; まだC++について 知らなくても大丈夫
In that case,
そのような方向けに
we've provided some resources that can help you get up to speed.
迅速な習得を助けるリソースを 用意してあります
You can use these resources to familiarize yourself with core C++
これらのリソースを使って C++の中核となる概念に慣れることで
concepts so that you can pass these challenges.
課題を クリアできます
The good news is that the C++ you'll use in this module
幸い このモジュールで使用するC++は
will look quite a bit like Python.
Pythonにかなり似ています
You should be fine with just the basics of control flow, functions, classes, and
制御フロー、関数、クラス、参照の 基本さえ知っていれば
references.
心配はありません
&gt;&gt; After that you'll be working with Andre and
&gt;&gt; その後 次の2つのレッスンでは
Dominic for the next two lessons.
アンドレイとドミニクが協力してくれます
&gt;&gt; Lidar and radar produce very different data.
&gt;&gt; ライダーとレーダーは 大幅に異なるデータを生成します
I'll help you implement a Kalman filter in C++ to fuse together data from both
2つのセンサーのデータを融合する カルマンフィルターを
of these sensors.
C++で実装するお手伝いをします
&gt;&gt; In my lesson, you'll perform sensor fusion with an unscented Kalman filter.
&gt;&gt; 私のレッスンでは アンセンテッドカルマンフィルターを使って センサーのデータを融合します
This is a different technique for object tracking that provides another tool for
これはオブジェクト追跡の もう1つの手法であり
handling non linear motion, such as a turning car or a bicycle.
方向を変える車や自転車などの非線形の動きを処理できる ツールを提供します
&gt;&gt; Okay, this is going to be fun.
&gt;&gt; 楽しくなりそうです
Let's get started.
それでは始めましょう
Michael, are you ready to show off your self driving car?
マイケル 自動運転車を披露する 準備はできていますか?
&gt;&gt; Definitely.
&gt;&gt; もちろん